<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lordpipe's Obscure Tutorials</title><link>https://lordpipe.github.io/obscure-tutorials/</link><description>Recent content on lordpipe's Obscure Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lordpipe.github.io/obscure-tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to install Fedora Minimal with Snapper</title><link>https://lordpipe.github.io/obscure-tutorials/docs/linux-tutorials/fedora-snapper/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lordpipe.github.io/obscure-tutorials/docs/linux-tutorials/fedora-snapper/</guid><description>The goal: Get a &amp;ldquo;riceable&amp;rdquo; Linux setup that can be rolled back in a flexible manner, by running a clever OpenSUSE tool on a non-OpenSUSE distro. Make a system that is difficult to break in a way that will waste a whole day getting it working again. All the fun of Linux desktop ricing, but none of the risk.
Skip introduction
Snapper? But what about Silverblue? # Silverblue is a fantastic project that intends to introduce the concept of immutable operating systems to the Linux desktop and server.</description></item><item><title>Tips for staying safe online</title><link>https://lordpipe.github.io/obscure-tutorials/docs/security-tips/safety/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lordpipe.github.io/obscure-tutorials/docs/security-tips/safety/</guid><description>The Russo-Ukrainian cyberwar has suddenly revealed many vulnerabilities in software and web services — many of which are now being used on random people. Below are some general tips for staying safe while playing Minecraft and using Discord, as well as some general internet safety advice, to lower your footprint to getting hacked or other problems.
This article is geared towards being advice for the staff of the UltraVanilla Minecraft server, but you may copy and adapt for your own use under the terms of the CC-BY license.</description></item><item><title>How to run a full malware checkup</title><link>https://lordpipe.github.io/obscure-tutorials/docs/security-tips/full-malware-checkup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lordpipe.github.io/obscure-tutorials/docs/security-tips/full-malware-checkup/</guid><description>This is a tutorial for cleaning up a computer. Aside from Microsoft Defender, the tools used are best for one-time use, and are not the best antivirus software for continuous protection.
Follow as many steps as you can, including the browser checkup tutorial at the end.
Windows and macOS # First, if on Windows, download and run BleepingComputer RKill. This will kill any actively running malware, so that Malwarebytes can do its job without any interference, as well as temporarily reset certain Windows settings to a predictable state.</description></item><item><title>How to enable automatic screen locking</title><link>https://lordpipe.github.io/obscure-tutorials/docs/security-tips/auto-screen-lock/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lordpipe.github.io/obscure-tutorials/docs/security-tips/auto-screen-lock/</guid><description>If you live with younger kids or hostile and/or idiotic family or roomates, you may wish to automatically lock your screen after a certain period of inactivity, to prevent unauthorized access.
Doing this is recommended if you are staff on UltraVanilla. If you work any sort of remote job you should be doing this!
Windows # Open Lock screen settings
Click Screen timeout
Click On resume, display login screen
Enter a wait time of 15 minutes</description></item><item><title>How to enable 2FA on a Discord account</title><link>https://lordpipe.github.io/obscure-tutorials/docs/security-tips/discord-2fa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lordpipe.github.io/obscure-tutorials/docs/security-tips/discord-2fa/</guid><description>Choosing a 2-factor authentication app # TOTP-based authentication is a standardized system, so there are different options to choose from:
App Platforms Has sync? Open source? Notes Authy ✅ ❌ Requires Snap on Linux. Has vendor lock-in — it will not show you your codes. Has better restore functionality than other apps Aegis ✅ ✅ Sync is via cloud storage API WinAuth ❌ ✅ Ravio ✅ ✅ Sync is via iCloud TOTP.</description></item><item><title>How to enable TOTP-based 2FA on a Microsoft account</title><link>https://lordpipe.github.io/obscure-tutorials/docs/security-tips/microsoft-2fa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lordpipe.github.io/obscure-tutorials/docs/security-tips/microsoft-2fa/</guid><description>Choosing a 2-factor authentication app # TOTP-based authentication is a standardized system, so there are different options to choose from:
App Platforms Has sync? Open source? Notes Authy ✅ ❌ Requires Snap on Linux. Has vendor lock-in — it will not show you your codes. Has better restore functionality than other apps Aegis ✅ ✅ Sync is via cloud storage API WinAuth ❌ ✅ Ravio ✅ ✅ Sync is via iCloud TOTP.</description></item></channel></rss>